CLAIRE HARDMAN

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER



+46 763416772



chardma3.github.io/hardman-dev



Stockholm



linkedin.com/in/claire-hardmandev



PROFILE

Full-Stack Development graduate from Code Institute 2021. I am highly organised and have experience of bringing projects from inception to completion in several fields such as video editing, photography and music. These industries require split second decisions in high pressure environments, decisive communication, a cool-head and attention to detail. I have strong communication skills in a multinational environment, am a passionate creator and empathetic leader. I am ready to take the next step in my life and bring all of these qualities to my career in tech.

EDUCATION

CODE INSTITUTE (ONLINE)

Diploma in Software Development

2020 - 2021 (1 year)

Graduated from Code Institute, with a diploma in Software Development through an intense Coding Bootcamp created and validated by tech industry experts and academics (Europe's only university credit-rated online coding Bootcamp - EQF & RQF, Level 5). Tech covered: HTML, CSS (incl. Bootstrap, Materialize), JavaScript, (incl. jQuery, JSON) Python, SQL & MongoDB, GitHub, Heroku, and Full-Stack Frameworks with Flask & Django. After graduation I continued to study React and Node.js through Udemy.

TAFE ARMIDALE, NSW, AUSTRALIA

Diploma in Screen (Distinction)

2004 - 2005 (2 years)

During this 2 year course I completed a number of commercial and private projects that I directed, produced and/or edited. At the end-of-year awards ceremony I won Best Director and a number of my projects were nominated for an award. I received highest marks upon completion and 3 months later landed a job as a video editor in the news room at the Australian Broadcasting Corporation (ABC) in Sydney. Course subjects covered include direction, video editing, cinematography and sound design.

EXPERIENCE

COMPOSER AND DJ

Claire Hardman Music (2010-present)

Consultative collaboration with clients before and during events to cater to a specific demographic. I also perform at clubs and festivals and compose my own music which has been released on distinguished international labels.

PHOTOGRAPHER/VIDEOGRAPHER

Hardman Photo (2011-2018)

Freelance photography and film projects for private individuals and companies.

chardma3.myportfolio.com

hardmanmusicofficial.com

PHOTOGRAPHERS ASSISTANT

Photographer Pelle Lundberg AB (2016-2019) Managing technical and client operations in a busy

commercial environment.

STUDIO ASSISTANT

H&M Photo Studios (2018)

Freelance studio operations role focused on technical equipment and ensuring production activities ran smoothly

DEV PROJECTS

PROJECTS COMPLETED THROUGHOUT THE CODE INSTITUTE COURSE

Project 4: Hardman Photo

A fully functioning E-commerce store allowing users to create an account, log in and out, update personal information and order pictures delivered to a given address and pay using Stripe payment service.

HTML | CSS | Javascript | Python | Django | Bootstrap AWS | Heroku | Git | Stripe | SQL

hardman-photo.herokuapp.com

Project 2: Summer Memories

A summer themed flip-card memory game built with object-oriented programming in JavaScript including sound fx and a moving gradient background.

HTML | CSS | Javascript | Git

chardma3.github.io/SummerMemories

Project 3: Best Bars

A bar review website allowing users to create an account, log in and out and publish, edit and delete reviews. Built with python, MongoDB database and micro-framework Flask.

HTML | CSS | Javascript | Python | Bootstrap | MongoDB Heroku | Git | Flask

best-bars.herokuapp.com

Project 1: Capino M/S

A single page application for a yacht entertainment service with a contact form for potential clients to contact the site owner.

HTML | CSS | Bootstrap | Git

chardma3.github.io/Capino

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Javascript ES6 | React | Node.JS | Python | Django | Flask
HTML | CSS | Bootstrap | SQL | NOSQL | AWS | MongoDB
Github | Heroku | Stripe | Balsamiq

OTHER PROGRAMS

Photoshop | Lightroom | Capture One | Final Cut Pro X | Adobe Premiere | Avid Ableton Live | Logic Pro X

LANGUAGES

- English (Native)
- Swedish (Fluent)
- Spanish (Beginner)

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

- Dj'd 2 Stadium Events (2019)
- Won 2 DJ competitions (2017, 2018)
- Released music on distinguished international record labels (2020-present)
- Won Years Best Director at Film and TV School (2005)
- University of New England's Women's Rugby Team
 Captain (2004-2005)
- Attended 3 university games for Rugby and Soccer (2003, 2004)
- Won a gold medal and selected as National University
 Women's Rugby Team Finalist (2004)